So one issue you are facing is that all the props are missing in our wrapped components, like the name
Kar karya olduunuzda, ad ve ya gibi paketlenmi bileenlerimizde tm sahne
and the age.
takmlarnn eksik olmas gerekiyor.
The reason for this is that in our higher order with class component, we're outputting wrapped component
Bunun nedeni, rap bileeni kardmz ancak sarlm bileen snf bileeniyle bir
but wrapped component can be either app.js or person.js.
saat yksek sipariin sa ya da Kii sa olabileceidir.
Now correctly both the title and the props the person.js components would expect are missing because
imdi doru hem balk hem de sahne tasarmcs, bekledii gibi kiinin eksik olduunu
these components get props
nk bu bileenler sahne alyor.
except for now they don't anymore because they are our wrapped component and we don't pass any props
imdi hari onlar artk bizim sargl bileen nk biz burada herhangi bir sahne
here.
gemek yok.
Now of course we can't hard code the props here because it's not like we have to pass name here,
Elbette sahne kodunu sabitleyemiyoruz nk burada ad gemek zorunda deiliz.
that would work for the person component but the app component or any other component we might wrap with
Bu, kii bileeni iin ie yarayabilir, ancak EP bileeni veya bununla rtebileceimiz
this might require totally different props.
dier bileenler tamamen farkl sahne gerektirir.
There is one single simple thing we should do, just pass on the existing props.
Var olan sahne zerinde gemesi gereken tek bir basit ey var.
Now how do you do that?
imdi bunu nasl yaparsn
You take advantage of an ES6 operator, the spread operator.
Siz onu yayma operatr olarak seks operatr olarak kullanrsnz.
Keep in mind that props are just an object, just an object of key value pairs.
Sahann yalnzca anahtar deer iftlerinin bir nesnesi olduuna dikkat edin.
Now you can output some dynamic content on this wrapped component,
Artk sarlm bileen zerinde baz dinamik ierik ktlayabilirsiniz.
with single curly braces and used the three dots, the spread operator on the props object to
Tek bir kvrml parantezi oturuyordu ve basite bu anahtar deer iftlerine blmek iin sahne parmak izi
simply split it up into these key value pairs and pass them to wrap component.
nesnesine serbest noktalar kullanyordu ve bileeni kaydrmak iin onlara geti.
This index might look strange at first but in the end it simply means pass on the props as you get them,
Bu indeks ilk bakta tuhaf grnebilir, ancak sonuta sadece sahada parmaklklar geerken, onlar
don't do anything else with them, just pass them on.
onlarla geirmeleri iin bir ey yapmazlar.
Split them up into key value pairs so that you can validly assign them to this wrapped component.
Onlar bln ve deerleri iftlerini tutarak, onlar geerli bir ekilde kaydrma bileenine atayabilirsiniz.
Now with that, if you save this you immediately see up on the reload
imdi onu kurtarrsanz hemen yklemeyi grrsnz.
the title is back and so is our person data and everything works as it did before.
Balk geri dnd ve bugnk verilerimiz ve her ey daha nce olduu gibi alyor.
So now we get a truly reusable higher order component and then there's this other thing I mentioned,
bileeni, burada olduu gibi ilevsel bir bileeni geri gndermek zorunda olmadn belirttiimiz baka ey var.
that this higher order component doesn't have to return a functional component as it does here,
imdi, gerekten tekrar kullanlabilir yksek mertebeden bir bileen alyor ve daha sonra bu yksek sipari
it depends on what you want to do in your higher order component.
Yksek sipari bileeninizde ne yapmak istediinize baldr.
If you need access to lifecycle hooks, for example if you plan on reaching out to the web and fetch the
Yaam dngs kancalarna erimeniz gerekiyorsa, rnein web'e ulamay planlyorsanz ve u anda
currently authenticated user and kind of do something with that,
kimlii dorulanan kullancy getirip tr bir eyle urarsanz.
if that's your plan you will need a stateful component and you can do that, going to copy that code
Eer plannz buysa, bir devletin tam bileenine ihtiya duyacaksnz ve bu kodu kopyalayacak
and comment it out up there
ve yinelenen blm orada yorumladrabilirsiniz.
and now simply insert it again,
Ve imdi tekrar tekrar cevaplad.
Instead of returning a function, you can also return a class which extends component or even your component
hatta dilerinizi yeniden aktarma bileeninden ie aktarmanz gereken tabii ki bileeninizi dndrebilirsiniz.
of course, which you then need to import from react component
Bir fonksiyonu dndrmek yerine, komponenti uzatan bir snf ya da
and now that we extended this, we have a normal syntax here
Ve imdi genilettik ki normal bir szdizimimiz var.
as you know it where we should have a render method, in the method render method,
Bildiiniz gibi, Meffert render ynteminde bir render yntemine sahip olmamz gerekir.
we will in the end return some jsx,
Sonunda baz j'yi x olarak dndrelim.
so just as we do in normal stateful components. And as always, the difference is props can be accessed
Normal durumsal bileenlerde yaptmz gibi ve her zaman olduu gibi bu sopayla
with this.props. So a normal stateful component, only difference is after the class keyword,
farkllklarn eriilebilecei gibi, bileenler iin normal bir durum yalnzca declasse anahtar szcnn farkllklarndandr.
there is no name because it's like an anonymous class, we're returning it, we're having a class factory
Hibir isim yok nk anonim bir snftr; bunun bir snf fabrikas olmas gerekiyordu. Burada,
here. We have a function that returns a class on demand and the class name doesn't matter,
MOND zerinde bir snf dndren ve snf ad nem tayan bir ileve sahip.
what matters to us is the render method which wraps our component with a div with
Bizim iin nemli olan, tamamlad render yntemi, bir div ile bir bileenidir.
in this case, a class name.
Bu durumda bir snf ad.
So now with that if I save it, works perfectly fine too,
imdi bunu kaydettiysem de ok iyi alyor.
now we got a wrapping component which is a class.
imdi bir snf olan sarc bir bileen var.
So these are higher order components and you saw some examples here,
Dolaysyla bunlar yksek sipari bileenleri ve burada baz rnekler grdnz.
You will see them again throughout the course
Kurs iin onlar bir daha grmeyeceksin.
and as I mentioned, there are a lot of third party packages which actually use higher order components
Ve bahsettiim gibi aslnda ok yksek sipari bileenleri kullanan ok sayda nc taraf paketleri var, bu
so that is also one form where you will see them a lot.
yzden hepsini bir araya getirecekleri bir forumda bulabilirsiniz.